Hwee Shan Wong

Software Engineer



About me

Hi, my name is Hwee and currently a software engineer in Natwest Group. I am passionate about developing tools and products to boost engineering experience. I have experience in delivering microservices using the twelvefactor app methodology, designing event-driven architecture and implementing infrastructure solutions and services.

Grew up trilingual (English, Mandarin, Malay).

Skills



Contact









Experience

Software Engineer, Enterprise Engineering Natwest Group, Edinburgh | since April 2018

- Automated the process of onboarding users to developer tools and technologies which reduced lead time from 48 hours to 5 mins.
- Delivered Spring Boot Java microservices in event-driven architecture and have deep understanding of the system design.
- Actively involved in decision making of system design and architecture improvements by collaborating closely with customers/SMEs.
- Cultivated behaviour-driven and test-driven development within the team which enhanced system reliability and team's DevOps metrics. Software development cycle time KPI reduced by 50%.
- Presented proof of concepts for various authentication/authorisation modules for tools which drove infrastructure and tooling improvements.
- Mentored junior engineers and continuously building best practices within the team such as codifying workflow using plantUML.

Technology Service Analyst

Natwest Group, Edinburgh | Sep 2017 - Apr 2018

- Responsible for migrating server data from bespoke tools to standardised ServiceNow Configuration Management Database for better consolidation of enterprise data.
- Automated data gathering and validation process for the migration work to ensure data quality was high and consistent.
- Drove the implementation of agile ways of working in my team through creation of manageable goals and Sprint boards.

Chemical Engineer

Merck, Sharp & Dohme (MSD), Newcastle | Aug 2015 - Sep 2016

- Supported technical operations in solid-dose tablet production facility and operated within GMP standards.
- Solved process deviations and problems by identifying root causes using Lean Six Sigma methodologies.



Education

MEng Chemical Engineering with Industrial Experience, University of Manchester

Sep 2013 - Jun 2017 First Class Honors

A Levels, Taylor's College Jan 2012 - Jun 2013 4A* in Chemistry, Biology, Physics, Mathematics



Contributions

Women In Tech Secretariat

Actively supporting gender balance within workplace. Running python workshops to promote software development.

STEM Ambassador

Encouraging students to appreciate Science, Technology, Engineering and Math (STEM) subjects by engaging them in interesting experiments and sharing Edinburgh and Glasgow work experience.

STV Big Scot Quiz Volunteer

Volunteered to assist and coordinate the running of a major, highprofile charity event that was held concurrently in which raised £35,000.